thedailybeast.com 2019-12-31

# Privacy Policy - The Daily Beast

## Privacy Policy

### As of December 20, 2019

The Daily Beast Company LLC has prepared this Privacy Policy to help you understand more about how we collect, use, and disclose information that we collect about consumers through our web and mobile services, which we refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as the “Services.”

This Privacy Policy only covers information that we collect about you as part of your use of the Services.

### What information do you collect about me?

The information that we collect about you falls into these general categories:

• Information that you provide. We may collect information that you choose to provide to us (including content that you submit to us or when you subscribe to our newsletter(s) or provide us with content for our site). This may include information such as your name, e-mail address, phone number, year of birth, gender, zip code, country, postal address, user name, password, and password reminder questions and answers. We may ask you for information when you register or subscribe, or at other times—such as when you enter a contest, take a survey, participate in a promotion, provide content, or order products from us. We may be required by law to collect certain personal data about you or as a consequence of any contractual relationship we have with you. Failure to provide this information may prevent or delay the fulfillment of these obligations.

• Automated information. Using technologies that are widely used on the Internet, such as cookies, web beacons, and other technologies, we also may automatically collect information about your computer or mobile device and online activity when you access the Services. For example, when you visit thedailybeast.com, we may collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and operating system, as well as information about which pages you visit and the page, if any, that referred you to our sites or that you visit after our sites. Similarly, when you use our mobile applications, we may collect information about your mobile device, such as the type of mobile device you use or your device identifier.

• Location information. When you use the Services, we may collect information about your location separately from your address or other information that you provide to us explicitly. For instance, we may use the GPS feature of your mobile device or your IP address to help determine your geographic location. If you prefer that we not know your geographic location, you will have the option to disable the function when you first use the service in which we collect information about your location (or later, if your mobile device allows you to change the settings after initial download). Disabling the geolocation function may prevent you from using certain features of our Services that require location information.

• Social networking information. If you log-in to The Daily Beast through a social networking account (e.g., Facebook or Twitter), we may collect information about you from that social networking account, including your name, email address, birthday, profile photograph, and other information associated with your social networking account.

• Information from other sources. We may combine the information that we collect with information that we obtain from other sources, such as our owners, including IAC, our past and present affiliates, including other IAC companies, and our business partners, licensees, contractors, and service providers. For example, we may ask a service provider to supply us with demographic information or updated contact information for you. For more information about the third parties from which we collect your personal data, please contact us at the contact information below.

### How do you use this information?

We use the information that we collect about you for these purposes:

• to contact you to provide information about The Daily Beast or other products or services in which we believe you may be interested, including newsletters, promotional emails, legal notices or information about changes to this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Use;

• to manage your account;

• to provide you with the products and services you request;

• to respond to your requests, questions, and comments;

• to perform business analyses or for other purposes to improve the quality of our business, the products and services we offer, including through surveys and questionnaires;

• to deliver targeted advertising, as described below;

• as we believe is necessary to protect our rights and the rights of others, including by enforcing our Terms of Use;

• and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.;

We also do research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to help us operate our Services, for other business purposes, and in connection with our display of advertising (which we describe below). This research is based on the information you provide to us including upon registration during a promotion, in surveys, and on your use of our Services.

### With whom do you share this information?

We may share the information that we collect about you through the Services in these ways:

• with authorized service providers that help us provide the Services or perform other business functions for us, such as sending emails or hosting web services (but these service providers are not permitted to use personal data that we provide for any purpose other than to provide service to us);

• with our corporate affiliates, licensees, and contractors, including the IAC family of businesses;

• in the context of contests or other promotions in which we identify an outside entity, with the identified entity;

• to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;

• when we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law;

• to enforce our Terms of Use and other agreements, or otherwise protect or defend our rights or property or the rights or property of others, or the safety of the public;

• in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale;

• in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable form;

• and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

In addition, if you provide content to the Services, such as submitting content through the “Your Turn” submission form as a part of The Daily Beast’s paid membership offering, any information that you submit will become public. It may become accessible through search engines or, if you sign in using credentials from a third-party social networking service, to users on that service. Unless otherwise noted, we do not limit the distribution of information that you share using these features.

The Daily Beast has implemented Google’s Invisible reCAPTCHA technology on our site. Use of the Invisible reCAPTCHA is subject to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) and [Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).

Our properties may feature Nielsen proprietary measurement software, which will allow you to contribute to market research, such as Nielsen TV Ratings. To learn more about the information that Nielsen software may collect and your choices with regard to it, please see [the Nielsen Digital Measurement Privacy Policy](http://priv-policy.imrworldwide.com/priv/browser/us/en/optout.html).

### How do you decide which advertisements to show me on the Services?

The Services are offered to you free of charge because we cover the cost of providing our Services by displaying advertisements. Many of these advertisements are targeted, which means that advertisers tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, men over 25 years old). The targeted ads on the Services may be provided by us, or they may be provided by a third-party vendor. We may use automated decision-making to customize your experience based on your personal information. You can learn more about targeted ads, including how to opt out of receiving them, below.

We also participate in affiliate advertising and allow affiliate links to be encoded on some of our pages. This means that we may earn a commission when you click on or make purchases via affiliate links and affiliate partners may use cookies to understand your use of the Services.

### Does this Privacy Policy apply to information collected through third-party offerings?

We sometimes partner with third parties that operate platforms or offer services that you can use to access or otherwise interact with our content and offerings. For example, you can access The Daily Beast on your Apple iPad or iPhone. Similarly, we may include in some of our Services features that integrate with third-party social networking services or other third-party services. To do this, we may include in our web pages and apps code from the social networking service provider or other third party. This code may allow the service provider to collect information about your activities. If you are logged into social networking or other third-party services at the time, the service providers may also be able to identify you in connection with that information.

Although this Privacy Policy will apply to our use of information collected about you through these co-branded offerings, we do not control the privacy practices of our third-party partners. As a result, we want you to be aware that when you use these offerings you may be providing information to both us and our partner, and you should review the partner’s privacy policy to be sure that you know how it will use any data that it collects.

The Daily Beast contains links to other sites, including third party payment processors and affiliate marketing links encoded by third parties. Please be aware that The Daily Beast is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal data. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by The Daily Beast. If you choose to purchase a product or service via our site, some special terms apply. Payments are handled by a third party payment processor, whose own terms and privacy policy will govern your transaction. We do not process, record or maintain your credit card, bank account or payment information, though the third party payment processor and/or the merchant may provide us with some data relating to your order, such as what you purchased and how much you spent, etc. We expressly disclaim any and all liability related to your use of any third party payment processor’s system, including its privacy practices. Also, we are not responsible for any fulfillment of product that you purchase from merchants or any issues relating to such product(s) or customer service.

### How do you protect the security of the information you store?

We have in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect through the Services. However, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us via the Services.

### How long do you keep the information you collect from me?

We retain the information we collect about and from you for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose we collected it for and for the purpose of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To provide security and business continuity for the activities described in this Privacy Policy, we may make backups of certain data, which we may retain for longer than the original data. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data we process, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your information, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

In some circumstances we may aggregate and de-identify your information in such a way that you may not reasonably be re-identified by us or any other company in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.

### What rights do I have regarding data about me?

If you would like to access, review, revise or delete personal data we have collected from you, please contact us as provided below. Your specific rights regarding access, review, revision or deletion your information is proscribed by local laws. Specific applicable local laws may be outlined below.

Legal rights applicable to personal data collected from individuals in the European Economic Area (“EEA”): Pursuant to the EU General Data Protection Regulation, natural persons (called data subjects) located in the EEA are afforded certain rights regarding their personal data, including the right access, correct, delete, restrict or object to our use of, and receive a portable copy in a usable electronic format of your personal data. You also may have the right withdraw any consent that you have previously provided to us and to lodge a complaint with your local data protection or privacy regulator.

If you would like to exercise any of the above rights, and the law of your jurisdiction requires us to honor that request, please send your request in writing to the address below. To assist us in processing your request in timely manner, please make your request in English if you are able to do so. Your request should include any information relevant to your request, including, without limitation: (i) your name, email and postal address; (ii) the specific right you are asserting (e.g., removal); and (iii) if you are requesting removal, a brief explanation of why you believe such information should be removed.

To help us prevent fraudulent removal requests, please also include a legible copy of a document that verifies your identity. You need not provide a government-issued document; a utility bill or similar mailing will suffice. You may also obscure parts of the document such as identifying numbers so long as the document continues to clearly identify you. If you are making the request on behalf of another person, please indicate your relationship to that person and provide evidence of your authority to make such request. All requests for removal will be reviewed by The Daily Beast’s legal and compliance team and we reserve the right, in compliance with applicable laws, to accept or reject, or make further inquiries regarding, any requests.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### Do you collect information from children?

We do not knowingly collect personal information (as that term is defined in the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database promptly.

### What are my California privacy rights?

California’s “Shine the Light” law permits residents of California to request certain details about what personal information (as that term is defined in California Civil Code § 1798.83) a company shares with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. Upon receipt of this notification, we will discontinue sharing your information for third party direct marketing purposes as soon as practicable.

The California Consumer Privacy Act, effective January 1, 2020, provides California “Consumers” with certain rights, as explained in our California Consumer Privacy Act Notice (“CCPA Notice”) below. Please review our CCPA Notice below for more information.

This CCPA Notice applies to “Personal Information” (also referred to herein as PI) of “Consumers” as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”).

We collect and share the following categories of PI from the corresponding sources and for the corresponding purposes set forth in the table below.

Category of Personal Information| Sources of Personal Information| Purposes for Collection| Categories of Third Parties with whom Personal Information is shared| Purposes of Third Parties Receiving PI  
---|---|---|---|---  
1\. Identifiers and Personal Records (e.g., email address, name, address, IP address, credit card number)| Directly from you; your devices; Vendors| Performing Services; Processing and managing interactions and transactions; Quality Assurance; security; debugging; marketing| Vendors which assist us in providing services and running our internal business operations (“Vendors”); Data Analytics Partners| Performing Services on our behalf; Processing and managing interactions and transactions; performing services; Quality Assurance; security; debugging  
2\. Customer Account Details / Commercial Information (e.g., details of your use of our service)| Directly from you; your devices| Performing Services; Research and development; quality assurance; security; debugging; and marketing| Data Analytics Partners; Vendors| Performing Services on our behalf; research and development; quality assurance; security; and debugging  
3\. Internet Usage Information (e.g., information regarding your interaction with our services)| You; your devices; Data Analytics Partners; Vendors| Research and development; quality assurance; security; and debugging| Data Analytics Partners; Vendors| Performing Services on our behalf; Research and development; quality assurance; security; and debugging  
4\. Geolocation Data| Your devices; Vendors| Performing Services; Processing and managing interactions and transactions; Quality Assurance; security; debugging; marketing| Vendors| Performing Services on our behalf; Processing and managing interactions and transactions; performing services; Quality Assurance; security; debugging  
5\. Inferences (e.g., your preferences, likelihood of interest in certain of our services)| Data Analytics Partners; Vendors; Advertising Networks| Research and development; quality assurance; and marketing| Data Analytics Partners; Vendors; Advertising Networks| Performing Services on our behalf; research and development; quality assurance; marketing  
  
In addition, we may collect, use and disclose your PI as required or permitted by applicable law, or as directed by you, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We do not knowingly “sell” personal information that we collect from you, in accordance with the definition of “sell” in the CCPA, and will treat personal information we collect from you as subject to a do not sell request. There is not yet a consensus as to whether third party cookies and tracking devices associated with our websites and mobile apps may constitute a “sale” of your PI as defined by the CCPA. You can exercise control over browser-based cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser. Further, you can learn more about your choices regarding certain kinds of online interest-based advertising here. We do not represent that these third-party tools, programs or statements are complete or accurate.

Some browsers have signals that may be characterized as do not track signals, but we do not understand them to operate in that manner or to indicate a do not sell expression by you so we currently do not recognize these as a do not sell request. We understand that various parties are developing do not sell signals and we may recognize certain such signals if we conclude such a program is appropriate.

California Consumers have the right to exercise the privacy rights under the CCPA. California Consumers may exercise these rights via an authorized agent who meets the agency requirements of the CCPA. Any request you submit to us is subject to an identification and residency verification process (“Verifiable Consumer Request”). We will not fulfill your CCPA request unless you have provided sufficient information for us to reasonably verify you are the Consumer about whom we collected PI. Please follow the instructions at our Consumer Rights Request page here and respond to any follow up inquiries we may make.

Some personal information we maintain about Consumers is not sufficiently associated with enough personal information about the Consumer for us to be able to verify that it is a particular Consumer’s personal information (e.g., clickstream data tied only to a pseudonymous browser ID). As required by the CCPA, we do not include that personal information in response to Verifiable Consumer Requests. If we cannot comply with a request, we will explain the reasons in our response.

We will make commercially reasonable efforts to identify Consumer PI that we collect, process, store, disclose, and otherwise use and to respond to your California Consumer privacy rights requests. We will typically not charge a fee to fully respond to your requests, but we may charge a reasonable fee, or refuse to act upon a request, if your request is excessive, repetitive, unfounded, or overly burdensome.

To make a request according to your rights to know or to request deletion of your PI set forth below, please email us at california-consumer-rights-request@thedailybeast.com or click here, where you will find a form to complete so that we can verify your identity using your email address and browser ID and fulfill your request as required by the CCPA. For your specific pieces of information, if required by the CCPA, we will apply heightened verification standards, which may include a request to provide further information.

You have the right to send us a request, no more than twice in a twelve-month period, for any of the following for the period that is twelve months prior to the request date:

  * The categories of PI we have collected about you.
  * The categories of sources from which we collected your PI.
  * The business or commercial purposes for our collecting or selling your PI.
  * The categories of third parties to whom we have shared your PI.
  * The specific pieces of PI we have collected about you.
  * A list of the categories of PI disclosed for a business purpose in the prior 12 months, or that no disclosure occurred.
  * A list of the categories of PI sold about you in the prior 12 months, or that no sale occurred. If we sold your PI, we will explain:
    * The categories of your PI we have sold.
    * The categories of third parties to which we sold PI, by categories of PI sold for each third party.

You have the right to make or obtain a transportable copy, no more than twice in a twelve-month period, of your PI that we have collected in the period that is 12 months prior to the request date and are maintaining.

Please note that PI is retained by us for various time periods, so we may not be able to fully respond to what might be relevant going back 12 months prior to the request.

Except to the extent we have a basis for retention under CCPA, you may request that we delete your PI that we have collected directly from you and are maintaining. Note also that we are not required to delete your PI that we did not collect directly from you.

You may alternatively exercise more limited control of your PI by instead exercising one of the following more limited opt-outs, including unsubscribing from email newsletters by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of a The Daily Beast email or sending an email to [tech@thedailybeast.com](mailto:tech@thedailybeast.com).

We will not discriminate against you in a manner prohibited by the CCPA because you exercise your CCPA rights. However, we may charge a different price or rate, or offer a different level or quality of good or service, to the extent that doing so is reasonably related to the value of the applicable data. In addition, we may offer you financial incentives for the collection, sale and retention and use of your PI as permitted by the CCPA that can, without limitation, result in reasonably different prices, rates, or quality levels. The material aspects of any financial incentive will be explained and described in its program terms. Please note that participating in incentive programs is entirely optional, you will have to affirmatively opt-in to the program and you can opt-out of each program (i.e., terminate participation and forgo the ongoing incentives) prospectively by following the instructions in the applicable program description and terms. We may add or change incentive programs and/or their terms by posting notice on the program descriptions and terms linked to above so check them regularly.

### What are cookies and web beacons and how are they used on the Services?

We use cookies and other technologies to store information on your computer or mobile device. We use this information for a variety of purposes, such as to remember you when you return to our websites or to identify your activities as you use certain Services. To do this, we may store a unique identifier on your computer or device. As described above, advertising service vendors that serve ads into our sites may also use their own cookies or identifiers.

You may opt out of the browser cookies delivered through the Services by changing the setting on your browser, such as through [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies), [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en), [Mozilla Firefox](http://kb.mozillazine.org/Cookies#Firefox), or [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042). Please be aware that this will disable all cookies delivered to your browser, not just the ones that we deliver, and that you may not be able to use all of the Services if you do not allow the placement of cookies. Also, opting out of browser cookies will not disable other technologies that we may use to collect information from you, including “Flash cookies.”

You also can opt out of receiving information stored in Adobe Local Shared Objects, which are commonly referred to as "Flash cookies." You can find more information about Local Shared Objects and how to disable them on Adobe’s website at [kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html](http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html). As with browser cookies, disabling Local Shared Objects may interfere with the proper functioning of the Services.

We or our third-party partners also may use technologies called web beacons that communicate information from your Internet browser to a web server. Web beacons can be embedded in web pages, videos, or emails, and can allow a web server to read certain types of information from your browser, check whether you have viewed a particular web page or email message, and determine, among other things, the time and date on which you viewed the web beacon, the IP address of your computer, and the URL of the web page from which the web beacon was viewed. We and our partners use web beacons for a variety of purposes, including analyzing the use of the Services and in conjunction with cookies to provide content and ads that are more relevant to you. You may disable our web beacons in email messages by turning off images in your email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see the instructions for your particular email client for more information. Please also be aware that by turning off images you may not be able to enjoy all of the Services as they were designed to be viewed.

### What choices do I have regarding your use of information about me?

Email messages. If you do not wish to receive emailed promotional material from us, you can opt out by clicking the unsubscribe mechanism in our promotional emails or by emailing us at [tech@thedailybeast.com](mailto:tech@thedailybeast.com). Please note that, even if you opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still contact you to provide you with non-commercial messages, such as legal notices. Also, if you opt out, we may not provide to you non-promotional material, such as our emailed newsletters and other content.

Google Ads opt out. If you would prefer not to receive advertisements through the Services that are targeted to your interests, you can inform our advertising vendor, Google, Inc., of your preference by clicking the "Opt out" button at [www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). You also can manage your advertising preferences at [www.google.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences).

Other targeted ads opt outs. In some cases, we and advertisers on the Services work with other third-party vendors to help deliver advertisements targeted to your interests. These vendors include ad networks and analytics providers, and they use cookies or other technologies to collect information about your online activity (e.g., the sites and pages you have visited) in order to help advertisers deliver particular ads that they believe you would find most relevant. Many third-party vendors that perform these functions are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, and you can opt out of those vendors’ delivery of targeted advertising to you by visiting [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Some of our Services use technology for this purpose provided by Adobe. You can express your preferences regarding Adobe’s use of information about you [here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html).

Please note that, because these opt-out tools will place a cookie on your computer to record your opt-out preference, any actions you take using these tools will apply only to the web browser that you use to take the action. Also, these tools may not work as expected if you set your browser to refuse cookies.

Sometimes, our advertisers will contract with a third-party service to host their ads. In this case, an ad-serving vendor contacts the advertisers’ hosting service to obtain a particular advertisement. Because we do not have a relationship with these third parties, we do not have a mechanism to allow visitors to opt out of tracking by these vendors.

### Is my data transferred internationally?

The Daily Beast Company LLC is headquartered in the United States. Please be aware that information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of the Services may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States or another country in accordance with applicable law. The privacy and data protection laws in another country may not be equivalent to such laws in your country of residence. By using and participating in the Services or providing us with your information, you understand that The Daily Beast will process your information in the United States.

### What happens when this Privacy Policy changes?

We may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy in accordance with applicable law, such as by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a notice on The Daily Beast website.

### Who should I contact if I have questions about this Privacy Policy?

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, you may contact us at: [tech@thedailybeast.com](mailto:tech@thedailybeast.com).

If you are located in the EEA and have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the manner in which your information is processed or would like to submit a request to us, please contact:

The Daily Beast  
Privacy Officer  
555 West 18th Street  
New York, NY 11215  

The Daily Beast Company LLC is the controller (as provided under laws applicable to EEA jurisdictions) responsible for the personal information we collect and process. We are represented in the EU by our subsidiary, IAC Search & Media UK, Ltd., which can be contacted at [Privacy@ask.co.uk](mailto:Privacy@ask.co.uk).

If you have questions or concerns regarding the way in which your personal information collected in the EEA is processed, please contact our Data Protection Officer at:

IAC Publishing, LLC  
Data Protection Officer  
555 12th St, Suite 300  
Oakland, CA 94607  

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. If, however, you believe that we have not been able to assist with your complaint or concern, you may have the right to make a complaint to the data protection authority of your country of residence.
